### Rajnish Trikaldarshi

└ +91 8789359890 • ☑ rajnish8singh9@gmail.com • in www.linkedin.com/in/rajnish-trikaldarshi

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Mobile app and web developer with over 3.9 years of experience, specializing in designing and delivering high-performance mobile apps and websites. Known for driving an increase 60% in user engagement through strategic design and development. A collaborative team player focused on improving project results 50% through innovation, excellence, and effective communication.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Development Skills:- React-Native, React JS, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML/CSS, Redux, Context API.
- Tools and Platforms: Open AI, Postman, Socket.io, Firebase, Clever-Tap, Mo-engage, Deployment, Xcode, Figma, Zeplin and Google Analytics.
- Version Control and Collaboration:- Bit-bucket, Git.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Software Engineer - Roothoot Pvt Ltd

Oct 2024 - Present

- Hyderabad, Telengana
  - Built high-performance mobile applications using React Native, improving app responsiveness and stability by 70%. Conducted thorough code reviews and resolved technical issues, maintaining a 65% improvement in overall code quality and significantly reducing bugs.
- Integrated elements of the user interface with server logic and third-party APIs, leading to a 80% improvement in the efficiency of system integration. Collaborated closely with team members and stakeholders, ensuring 70% faster project completion and strict adherence to project specifications.

# Associate Software Engineer – Daffodil Software

August 2021 – Sept 2024

- Hisar, Harvana
- · High-quality mobile applications were created using React Native, enhancing the speed of the application and the user experience by 45%. Regularly performed code reviews and resolved issues, maintaining a 40% improvement in code reliability and development standards.
- Integrated mobile applications with servers and third-party APIs, achieving a 45% improvement in integration speed and reliability. Collaborated with team members and stakeholders to complete projects 40% faster while consistently meeting all expectations..

#### PROJECTS

## Xperiensys - Roothoot Pvt Ltd

Oct 2024 - Present

- Hyderbad, Telengana
- $\bullet$  Built and optimized responsive user-facing screens with React Native and React JS, achieving 100% cross-platform compatibility and improving data sharing efficiency by 30% through native modules.
- Integrated Firebase for real-time notifications, resulting in a 65% improvement in user engagement. Successfully deployed the application on Android and iOS, collaborated through Figma for seamless design handoff, and optimized performance monitoring with Google Analytics for a 60% boost in operational efficiency.

# Floom - Journal Community App - Daffodil Software

Sept 2021 – Jan 2024

- Hisar, Haryana
- Developed user-facing screens and elements using React JS, React Native, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Integrated third-party APIs including Firebase, Clever-Tap, Moengage, and Open AI. Managed notifications and app links using Firebase.
- Worked on native modules and sharing intents for data sharing across apps and platforms. Deployed the app on both Android and iOS, utilising tools like Google Analytics and Figma for performance tracking and design collaboration.

# Raga Therapy - Daffodil Software

Jan 2022 – Aug 2022

Hisar, Haryana

• Developed user interfaces using React JS, React Native, HTML, CSS and JavaScript, improving app responsiveness and design efficiency by 45%. Integrated third-party APIs, implemented post and app sharing via Firebase, and deployed the app on both Android and iOS, achieving a 40% increase in user engagement and performance.

### **Verbee** – Daffodil Software

https://verbee.ai/.

Hisar, Haryana

- Created user interfaces with React JS, React Native, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Integrated third-party APIs
- Implemented app and post sharing links using Firebase. Deployed the app on both Android and iOS. Utilised Google Analytics and Figma for performance tracking and design.

and implemented Open AI services including Azure, Claude, and Chat-GPT. This project can be viewed at

Locomo – Daffodil Software

Jan 2023 - Sept 2024

June 2023 - Sept 2024

Hisar, Haryana

• Developed user interfaces with React JS, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Integrated third-party APIs, implemented app and post sharing links using Firebase, managed notifications, and integrated Firebase analytics with Google Analytics. This project can be viewed at https://locomo.lo/.

#### EDUCATION

Govt. Polytechnic, Hisar • Hisar, Haryana

August 2018 – August 2021

Polytechnic • Computer Science Engineering • CGPA: 8.5

**R.D.Public School, Tekari** • Gaya, Bihar Secondary Education • 10th(CBSE) • CGPA: 9.5

August 2018